He's been chased, thrown through a window and arrested. Eddie
Murphy is a Detroit cop on vacation in Beverly Hills.
Beverly Hills Cop is a comedy, crime, action film directed by Martin Brest.
Fast-talking, quick-thinking Detroit street cop Axel Foley has bent more than a few rules and regs in his time, but
when his best friend is murdered, he heads to sunny Beverly Hills to work the case like only he can.
Axel Foley, played by Eddie Murphy.
Det. Billy Rosewood, played by Judge Reinhold.
Sgt. Taggart, played by John Ashton.
Jenny Summers, played by Lisa Eilbacher.
Lt. Bogomil, played by Ronny Cox.
Victor Maitland, played by Steven Berkoff.
Beverly Hills Cop II is a 1987 American buddy cop action comedy film directed by Tony
Scott, written by Larry Ferguson and Warren Skaaren, and starring Eddie Murphy.
It is the sequel to the 1984 film Beverly Hills Cop and the second
installment in the Beverly Hills Cop film series.
Murphy returns as Detroit police detective Axel Foley, who reunites with Beverly Hills detectives Billy Rosewood (Judge Reinhold) and John
Taggart (John Ashton) to stop a criminal organization after Captain Andrew Bogomil (Ronny Cox) is shot and seriously wounded.
The film was released on May 20, 1987, by Paramount Pictures.
It received mixed reviews from critics on release, but it was a box
office success, grossing $300 million worldwide.
Additionally, the film was nominated for an Oscar, as well as a Golden Globe
Award for Best Original Song, for Bob Seger's "Shakedown".
Two sequels, Beverly Hills Cop III and Beverly Hills Cop:
Axel F, were released in 1994 and 2024.
The film explores themes of showdown, drug
smuggling, undercover, cocaine, strip club.
The tone is lighthearted.